so this video is about my disabilities
my health challenges and how they
intersect the intersectionality of my
disabilities I I feel that almost every
one of the traits that I have is rather
low on the spectrum of that trait I have
single-sided deafness but I don't have
tinnitus with it I don't have I still
have rather perfect hearing in my other
ear which is both a blessing and a curse
if your single sided deaf you can you
can understand but there's the statistic
that I read was 30% of people become
single sided deaf in their adult life go
on to not be able to work and I get that
because it is very difficult to be in a
binary hearing world when you don't have
when you're single sighted because you
can't cancel it background noise and you
it's just exhausting to live in the
regular world so the world is exhausting
for me and I have chronic fatigue and
what chronic fatigue is for some people
it's it's devastating they cannot get
out of bed they cannot do absolutely
anything like a walk to the washroom is
all they can do in a day
some can't even do that mine is less
than that as long as I don't do cardio
as long as my heart rate doesn't get up
I seem to do okay but my body doesn't
recover from which it was just a sign of
chronic fatigue that your body doesn't
restore itself with sleep so I restore
myself a little bit with sleep but
nowhere near what someone without
chronic fatigue does and yet not
anywhere near as bad as what somebody
with very devastating chronic fatigue
has I have myalgia which is
chronic pain it's kind of unexplained
all throughout my body but there are
things that I can do that cause no pain
I don't walk like I'm in pain because it
doesn't help to walk any differently
it's just different if I like hurt my
ankle or hurt my knee then I need to
walk on it more softly I have arthritis
which is when you get in a pain cycle
your body starts creating more pain so
it's kind of hard to deal with the
neurological mental part of fibromyalgia
I also have arthritis but
figured it out and I'm dealing with that
I have sensory processing disorder which
I have been diagnosed with which is a
subset of autism like it's bar under the
autism umbrella but not when I got
diagnosed with it so sounds can trigger
me some lights can trigger me smells can
trigger me and it puts me into fight
flight or freeze mode generally freeze
generally but sometimes fight or flight
and like I need to get away from it's
actually flight is is one so I feel like
I'm definitely missing more of my
diagnosis ease anxiety which is also
kind of a lot of people who end up
figuring out they have autism anxiety
their whole lives probably because you
feel like you don't fit in and you need
to figure out how to fit in so you get
some amount of social interaction cuz
you still I still how'd that mean that
the single-sided deafness makes me tired
the chronic fatigue means that I can't I
can't recuperate as well the
fibromyalgia and arthritis students my
body's in pain which uses more energy
and so as long as I deal with my spoons
which is a metric for energy then that
has has developed it in the energy
disability community that as long as I
can budget my spoons I do okay but as
soon as I've had one bad day can it can
lead into the next and lead into the
next and it's really hard to recover
them so I have to make sure that I keep
myself warm so that I'm not using extra
energy to do things like that I have to
make sure and there's a lot of things
that are like it's finding the balance
if my house is clean my anxiety is doing
better my everything is better right
it's easier to move around takes less
energy to move around a clean house but
cleaning my house takes energy so it's
almost always gonna get messy eventually
because I'm gonna have a bad day and
it's I'm not gonna have students and
it's gonna end and I have a TD like and
I think so I do I have a hard time
keeping my house clean and yet the
opposite affects me I if I was to eat
very healthy it would probably lessen a
lot of my symptoms but I don't have the
energy to eat healthy or the executive
functioning to do it so
I don't and that was actually the one of
the biggest jumps in my health was
letting go of this rigid what is healthy
and what's not now I've got to go back
the other way and figure out how to how
to eat healthy within my capacity of
spoons and executive functioning I feel
like I'm gonna get off of this and
totally remember something that is oh my
neurological stuff so since my radiation
my brain is just weird like it it'll
hold on to sensations for a really long
time like if I'm nauseous
it will continually be nauseous for
weeks or but then sometimes it won't
it's like I have a coffee now and when
I've had a coffee in the past it's like
it becomes Tourette's like I don't have
Tourette's but it becomes like this
neurological pathway that it will just
keep following until it lets it go and I
also just have weird neurological
sensations I'll smell things that aren't
there
or I will feel things on my body that I
know aren't there but since I know
they're not there I'm fine
everyone smell like I'll feel something
probably on me and I'll go to leg it
should or get it off it'll be like an
actual thing and that will be you
that'll definitely freaked me out
because I'm so used to it not being
something so I have a lot of different
conditions I have changed the story from
oh woe is me
c'mon why do I have all these things -
well one I don't have them all none of
them are terrible by themselves it's
only the intersectionality of them that
makes it so I can't work it makes it so
that my life is reduced and that they
truly are a blessing because they've let
me see into people's lives that have all
of these things much more strongly and
they have much more of a devastating
impact so I can create a world that
works for everyone if I didn't have
these limitations I wouldn't have as
much empathy I wouldn't have as much
understanding for misunderstanding what
other people are going through like I'm
like right I get that you you don't
experience life in my body I get what
this looks like from the outside versus
inside and if
I can't go by your judgment of my life I
can't judge your life either and so I
look at my all of my disabilities as a
blessing because they are part of what
I'm here to do they've also helped me
get over I would say 90% of my ableism
there's still some some ableism in there
but it's it's what I'm here to do and
the intersectionality of them is what
helps Thanks